# lan Matsumoto

#### DATA ANALYST

# CONTACT



Berkeley, CA



808-679-7230



ianmat55@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Ian Matsumoto is a GIS Analyst, freelancer and programmer. Travelling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic

# **EDUCATION**

#### University of Redlands

2015 - 2019

Major:

Envoronmental Science

GIS

Minor:

Mathematics

# SKILLS

# Technologies:

GIS based systems

Git

Lidar and remote sensing

## Languages:

Python

Java

Some JavaScript

## Professional:

Project management and QA processing

New hire training

Workflow coordination

Technical writing

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Use the Tesla autopilot labeling interface to identify areas critical to training the neural network
- Collaborate with computer vision engineers to help improve the design of efficient labelling interfaces
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct daily feedback reporting for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.

## Freelance Web Developer

2/2021 - present

Self-taught programmer specializing in website development using Wordpress and Shopify.

- Create websites for clients using html, css and javascript
- Work with hosting platforms, content management systems and APIs
- Specialize in commerce development as well as personal/professional website development

# GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems | 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps  $\,$ 

- Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- Update Apple maps and record all projects of different priorities across multiple timelines
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects